<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Hugo-Du</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Hugo-Du</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://dupractice.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Book Review: R as GIS for economist</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/09/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 08:00:21 -1600</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/09/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Chapter 3. Spatial Interactions of Vector Data: Subsetting and Joining 3.2 Spatial Subsetting Could help researchers to narrow down the geographic scope of analysis.
# ------ Subsetting ------ # # select only the grid that intersect with eez grid_1 &amp;lt;- grid[eez,] # the default underlying topological relations is st_intersects() grid_2 &amp;lt;- grid[eez, , op = st_within] # change op = # ------ Joining(will still use the target gis) ------ # # point(target) vs polygon(source) st_join(wells, eez) # target first # polygons vs polysons IA_corn &amp;lt;- readRDS(&amp;#34;Data/IA_corn.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: R as GIS for economist</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/08/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/08/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Chapter 2. Vector Data Handling with sf sf
do not need to create simple feature geometry from scratch.
An important feature of an sf object is that it is basically a data.frame with geometric information stored as a variable (column). This means that transforming an sf object works just like transforming a data.frame. Basically, everything you can do to a data.frame, you can do to an sf as well.</description></item><item><title>Multiple ways to import text data in R</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/01/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/01/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Past Reading text files is always the first step when analyzing the text data. However, it could be challenging. Before I get to know the package &amp;lsquo;readtext&amp;rsquo;, I used to write a loop to import data like the following code.
# Step one in this approach is grabbing the list of files. file.list&amp;lt;-list.files() file.list # Step two in this approach is setting up the loop for(i in 1:length(file.list)){ temp&amp;lt;-import(file.list[i]) if(i==1){amdts&amp;lt;-temp} else{amdts&amp;lt;-bind_rows(amdts,temp)} print(paste(&amp;#34;Loading file&amp;#34;,i,&amp;#34;of&amp;#34;,length(file.</description></item><item><title>Gridding data in R</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/29/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/29/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>I am pushing forward one of my projects, in which I wish to analyze on the grid level instead of on the administrative level. This kind of aggregation is popular in several studies, name a few, Besley and Reynal-Querol (2014) , Michalopoulos and Papaioannou (2016) , and Berman, et al (2017) . While I was doing that, I confronted several problems and finally figured them out.
Reference in stackoverflow (Notice that the code on this page could be wrong):</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python III</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/28/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/28/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>In this document, we continue our study on basics of Python.
Method In Python, a method is a function that is associated with an object. It only works with that object It is used with dot notation: object.method()
Check more list methods here String methods here cars = [&amp;#39;Ford&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;BMW&amp;#39;] cars.append(&amp;#39;Mazda&amp;#39;) print(cars) cars.sort() print(cars) Function In Python, a function is a named block of code that performs a specific task or set of operations.</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python II</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Recap In When a R user began coding with Python I , we learn about:
the IDEs, mathematical operations, basic data types, variables, branching, and iteration comparison and logical operators This document In this document, we push forward the learning process and focus on four data structures used to store and organize data: list, dictionary, and tuple.
List: A list is an ordered collection of items, and it can contain elements of different data types.</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python I</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/20/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/20/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Excited to start my journey in Python!
I am a R user and always tell myself it is already enough to master one language. But this summer I attended to the ICPSR Sumer Program in Quantitative Methods and enrolled several exciting courses, such as Text Analysis and the Introduction to Python. I thought it’s time to learn something new!
Why Python? Actually, I learn Python because I want to push forward one of my text-analysis projects, which I need to scrap data from Weibo first.</description></item><item><title>News Collection: Climate and Environment</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/05/01/second-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 13:37:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/05/01/second-post/</guid><description>This is a collection of newspaper articles related to climate and the environment, which I am interested in.
Climate change Anger Builds in Towns Deliberated Flooded, in Part, to Save Beijing, NYT, Agu/4/2023, link . What This Year&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Astonishing&amp;rsquo; Ocean Heat Means for the Planet, NYT, Aug/3/2023, link . The extreme heat is devastating Florida’s coral reefs, but high ocean temperatures can have more widespread impacts, too, disrupting other marine ecosystems and the communities that depend on them.</description></item><item><title>Markdown 试水</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/cn/2021/01/07/first-post-cn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 13:42:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/cn/2021/01/07/first-post-cn/</guid><description>如果好奇以下的内容是如何实现的，请参考本页源代码 。
第一级标题 第二级标题 第三级标题 第四级标题 第五级标题 第六级标题 列表 Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water 表格 Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water1 Water Water Water Water 引语 知之为知之，不知为不知，是知也2。 — 孔子
数学公式 最简单的如，$1 + 1 = 3$</description></item><item><title>Markdown Testing</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2021/01/07/second-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 13:37:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2021/01/07/second-post/</guid><description>See the source code of this page if you are interested.
H1 H2 H3 H4 H5 H6 List Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Table Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water1 Water Water Water Water Quotes What I cannot create, I do not understand2.</description></item><item><title>Bookdown 和 ElegantBookdown 使用心得</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/cn/2020/05/26/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/cn/2020/05/26/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>最近的一周一直在调试 Bookdown 。其实，Bookdown 本身并不难，益辉大神 在他的那本 bookdown: Authoring Books and Technical Documents with R Markdown 已经介绍的非常清楚。我一直在调试的、也是我一直不会的主要集中在 PDF 的样式上，比如：
PDF 中的 &amp;ldquo;Chapter 1&amp;rdquo; 如何改成「第一章」？ HTML 上改的话比较容易。如果你也是用的 bookdown-demo 来开始的话，那么在根目录下找到 _bookdown.yml 这个文档，然后把 chapter_name: &amp;quot;Chapter &amp;quot; 改成 chapter_name: [&amp;quot;第 &amp;quot;, &amp;quot; 章&amp;quot;]1 就好了。
注意，这里标点是英文的。汉字和第二个英文引号之间有一个英文空格，是为了让版面更漂亮一些。不加空格的话，就是 「第N章」，加上空格就是「第 N 章」，所以还是加上吧。
但是，PDF 中还是显示 「Chapter N」。我知道肯定能改，但我感觉比较困难，所以就放弃了。虽然可能只是在 preamble.tex 里加一行代码的事，但我可能要花几天的时间才能知道那行代码是啥。果断放弃。
PDF 的空白页如何删除？
PDF 如何上每一页的文本对齐，而非 bookdown 预设的那样一左一右？
PDF 中如何更改中文引语的字体？
等等。
我知道是我要求太苛刻了。Bookdown 原本主要是为网页版书籍准备的，而非 PDF 版。因此，Bookdown 官网 上摆出的那些书籍中，有一些根本就没有把 PDF 版放上去。</description></item><item><title>背影</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/cn/1925/10/01/beiying/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 1925 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/cn/1925/10/01/beiying/</guid><description>我与父亲不相见已二年余了，我最不能忘记的是他的背影。那年冬天，祖母死了，父亲的差使也交卸了，正是祸不单行的日子，我从北京到徐州，打算跟着父亲奔丧回家。到徐州见着父亲，看见满院狼藉的东西，又想起祖母，不禁簌簌地流下眼泪。父亲说，“事已如此，不必难过，好在天无绝人之路！”
　回家变卖典质，父亲还了亏空；又借钱办了丧事。这些日子，家中光景很是惨淡，一半为了丧事，一半为了父亲赋闲。丧事完毕，父亲要到南京谋事，我也要回北京念书，我们便同行。
　到南京时，有朋友约去游逛，勾留了一日；第二日上午便须渡江到浦口，下午上车北去。父亲因为事忙，本已说定不送我，叫旅馆里一个熟识的茶房陪我同去。他再三嘱咐茶房，甚是仔细。但他终于不放心，怕茶房不妥帖；颇踌躇了一会。其实我那年已二十岁，北京已来往过两三次，是没有甚么要紧的了。他踌躇了一会，终于决定还是自己送我去。我两三回劝他不必去；他只说，“不要紧，他们去不好！”
　我们过了江，进了车站。我买票，他忙着照看行李。行李太多了，得向脚夫行些小费，才可过去。他便又忙着和他们讲价钱。我那时真是聪明过分，总觉他说话不大漂亮，非自己插嘴不可。但他终于讲定了价钱；就送我上车。他给我拣定了靠车门的一张椅子；我将他给我做的紫毛大衣铺好坐位。他嘱我路上小心，夜里警醒些，不要受凉。又嘱托茶房好好照应我。我心里暗笑他的迂；他们只认得钱，托他们直是白托！而且我这样大年纪的人，难道还不能料理自己么？唉，我现在想想，那时真是太聪明了！
　我说道，“爸爸，你走吧。”他望车外看了看，说，“我买几个橘子去。你就在此地，不要走动。”我看那边月台的栅栏外有几个卖东西的等着顾客。走到那边月台，须穿过铁道，须跳下去又爬上去。父亲是一个胖子，走过去自然要费事些。我本来要去的，他不肯，只好让他去。我看见他戴着黑布小帽，穿着黑布大马褂，深青布棉袍，蹒跚地走到铁道边，慢慢探身下去，尚不大难。可是他穿过铁道，要爬上那边月台，就不容易了。他用两手攀着上面，两脚再向上缩；他肥胖的身子向左微倾，显出努力的样子。这时我看见他的背影，我的泪很快地流下来了。我赶紧拭干了泪，怕他看见，也怕别人看见。我再向外看时，他已抱了朱红的橘子望回走了。过铁道时，他先将橘子散放在地上，自己慢慢爬下，再抱起橘子走。到这边时，我赶紧去搀他。他和我走到车上，将橘子一股脑儿放在我的皮大衣上。于是扑扑衣上的泥土，心里很轻松似的，过一会说，“我走了；到那边来信！”我望着他走出去。他走了几步，回过头看见我，说，“进去吧，里边没人。”等他的背影混入来来往往的人里，再找不着了，我便进来坐下，我的眼泪又来了。
　近几年来，父亲和我都是东奔西走，家中光景是一日不如一日。他少年出外谋生，独力支持，做了许多大事。那知老境却如此颓唐！他触目伤怀，自然情不能自已。情郁于中，自然要发之于外；家庭琐屑便往往触他之怒。他待我渐渐不同往日。但最近两年的不见，他终于忘却我的不好，只是惦记着我，惦记着我的儿子。我北来后，他写了一信给我，信中说道，“我身体平安，惟膀子疼痛利害，举箸提笔，诸多不便，大约大去之期不远矣。”我读到此处，在晶莹的泪光中，又看见那肥胖的，青布棉袍，黑布马褂的背影。唉！我不知何时再能与他相见！</description></item></channel></rss>