<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Hugo-Du</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Hugo-Du</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dupractice.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gridding data in R</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>I am pushing forward one of my projects, in which I wish to analyze on the grid level instead of on the administrative level. This kind of aggregation is popular in several studies, name a few, Besley and Reynal-Querol (2014) , Michalopoulos and Papaioannou (2016) , and Berman, et al (2017) . While I was doing that, I confronted several problems and finally figured them out.
Reference in stackoverflow (Notice that the code on this page could be wrong):</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python II</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Recap In When a R user began coding with Python I , we learn about:
the IDEs, mathematical operations, basic data types, variables, branching, and iteration comparison and logical operators This document In this document, we push forward the learning process and focus on four data structures used to store and organize data: list, dictionary, and tuple.
List: A list is an ordered collection of items, and it can contain elements of different data types.</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python III</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>In this document, we continue our study on basics of Python.
Method In Python, a method is a function that is associated with an object. It only works with that object It is used with dot notation: object.method()
Check more list methods here String methods here cars = [&amp;#39;Ford&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;BMW&amp;#39;] cars.append(&amp;#39;Mazda&amp;#39;) print(cars) cars.sort() print(cars) Function In Python, a function is a named block of code that performs a specific task or set of operations.</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python I</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/20/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/20/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Excited to start my journey in Python!
I am a R user and always tell myself it is already enough to master one language. But this summer I attended to the ICPSR Sumer Program in Quantitative Methods and enrolled several exciting courses, such as Text Analysis and the Introduction to Python. I thought it’s time to learn something new!
Why Python? Actually, I learn Python because I want to push forward one of my text-analysis projects, which I need to scrap data from Weibo first.</description></item></channel></rss>