<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English blog on Hugo-Du</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/blog/</link><description>Recent content in English blog on Hugo-Du</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://dupractice.github.io/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python II</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Recap In When a R user began coding with Python I , we learn about:
the IDEs, mathematical operations, basic data types, variables, branching, and iteration comparison and logical operators This document In this document, we push forward the learning process and focus on four data structures used to store and organize data: list, dictionary, and tuple.
List: A list is an ordered collection of items, and it can contain elements of different data types.</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python III</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>In this document, we continue our study on basics of Python.
Method In Python, a method is a function that is associated with an object. It only works with that object It is used with dot notation: object.method()
Check more list methods here String methods here cars = [&amp;#39;Ford&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;BMW&amp;#39;] cars.append(&amp;#39;Mazda&amp;#39;) print(cars) cars.sort() print(cars) Function In Python, a function is a named block of code that performs a specific task or set of operations.</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python I</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/20/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/20/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Excited to start my journey in Python!
I am a R user and always tell myself it is already enough to master one language. But this summer I attended to the ICPSR Sumer Program in Quantitative Methods and enrolled several exciting courses, such as Text Analysis and the Introduction to Python. I thought it’s time to learn something new!
Why Python? Actually, I learn Python because I want to push forward one of my text-analysis projects, which I need to scrap data from Weibo first.</description></item><item><title>Markdown Testing</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2021/01/07/second-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 13:37:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2021/01/07/second-post/</guid><description>See the source code of this page if you are interested.
H1 H2 H3 H4 H5 H6 List Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Table Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water1 Water Water Water Water Quotes What I cannot create, I do not understand2.</description></item><item><title>The Road Not Taken</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/1915/01/01/road-not-taken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1915 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/1915/01/01/road-not-taken/</guid><description>Two roads diverged in a yellow wood,
And sorry I could not travel both
And be one traveler, long I stood
And looked down one as far as I could
To where it bent in the undergrowth;
Then took the other, as just as fair,
And having perhaps the better claim,
Because it was grassy and wanted wear;
Though as for that the passing there
Had worn them really about the same,</description></item></channel></rss>