<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English blog on Hugo-Du</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/blog/</link><description>Recent content in English blog on Hugo-Du</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://dupractice.github.io/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GEE: Data Download</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/23/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:00:21 -1100</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/23/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>In this document, I will give an example to display how to download satellite data via Python API, and I will use Colab to program.
Case: Download Landsat 7 Collection 1 Tier 1 Annual NDVI Composite Earth Engine Data Catalog already lists all available collections. You can easily search out the one your project needs.
Actually, selecting appropriate collections could be a challenge if you are not familiar with the satellite data.</description></item><item><title>LLMs for Economics Research</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/23/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 10:00:21 -1100</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/23/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>参加了学院的大语言模型(LLM)在经济学研究的workshop，学到/想到了几点：
ChatGPT如何正确地写prompt(提示语)？目前来说最有效的方法是给例子，把想做的input/output举两三个例子给模型，能有效提高输出质量。
ChatGPT的网页版本跟API版本相比差距明显，做研究的时候用API版本并且把temperature参数调成0，基本上可以复现结果。
目前LLM+OCR已经在路上，预计明年推出，到时候可以文本扫描配合语意理解一条龙输出结果，可以将特别杂乱的数据完全规整。我的看法是LLM在未来的学术研究中一定会是重要的一环，特别是在原来数据获取难度特别高的领域，例如经济史等领域。有了更低的数据获取难度，能帮研究者更加聚焦在研究问题本身，或许会有新发展。
学术研究里编程语言应该投向Python。Kevin Bryan直接说大家应该放弃Stata，maybe放弃R。原因在于目前太多代码数据都基于Python，在编程上遇到任何问题基本上都能让ChatGPT完美解决，但是Stata和R的训练文本不足，出来的结果还是有非常多错漏。在AI时代，这样的差距将会越来越明显。
我的个人看法是，英语在未来将会越来越重要，能够利用英语阅读和写作的能力所带来的价值将会越来越高。原因就在于目前所有的高质量文本都在英语世界，如科普文章，编程教程，科研成果等。训练文本的质量和数量直接决定了模型的能力，只有在英文环境下才能用上最好的模型来解决问题。比如说Cohere公司做的embedding model，其他语言只能做到768个dimension，但是英语可以做到4096个dimension，出来的效果会更好。未来人类大概率要用LLM来帮助我们解决一切问题，不懂英语会是一个非常大的劣势。</description></item><item><title>GEE: Introduction</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/22/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/22/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Why the GEE? Data from the Google Earth Engine (GEE) is getting more and more popular in social science research. As a cloud-based geospatial analysis platform, GEE provides various geospatial remote sensing collections, such as forestation, climate monitoring, and land cover data. Gorelick et al. 2017 listed the most frequently used datasets in the GEE.
GEE has been used to address several societal issues. For example, in 2013, Hansen et al.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: R as GIS for economist</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/09/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 08:00:21 -1600</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/09/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Chapter 3. Spatial Interactions of Vector Data: Subsetting and Joining 3.2 Spatial Subsetting Could help researchers to narrow down the geographic scope of analysis.
# ------ Subsetting ------ # # select only the grid that intersect with eez grid_1 &amp;lt;- grid[eez,] # the default underlying topological relations is st_intersects() grid_2 &amp;lt;- grid[eez, , op = st_within] # change op = # ------ Joining(will still use the target gis) ------ # # point(target) vs polygon(source) st_join(wells, eez) # target first # polygons vs polysons IA_corn &amp;lt;- readRDS(&amp;#34;Data/IA_corn.</description></item><item><title>Book Review: R as GIS for economist</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/08/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/08/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Chapter 2. Vector Data Handling with sf sf
do not need to create simple feature geometry from scratch.
An important feature of an sf object is that it is basically a data.frame with geometric information stored as a variable (column). This means that transforming an sf object works just like transforming a data.frame. Basically, everything you can do to a data.frame, you can do to an sf as well.</description></item><item><title>Multiple ways to import text data in R</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/01/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/01/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Past Reading text files is always the first step when analyzing the text data. However, it could be challenging. Before I get to know the package &amp;lsquo;readtext&amp;rsquo;, I used to write a loop to import data like the following code.
# Step one in this approach is grabbing the list of files. file.list&amp;lt;-list.files() file.list # Step two in this approach is setting up the loop for(i in 1:length(file.list)){ temp&amp;lt;-import(file.list[i]) if(i==1){amdts&amp;lt;-temp} else{amdts&amp;lt;-bind_rows(amdts,temp)} print(paste(&amp;#34;Loading file&amp;#34;,i,&amp;#34;of&amp;#34;,length(file.</description></item><item><title>Gridding data in R</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/29/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/29/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>I am pushing forward one of my projects, in which I wish to analyze on the grid level instead of on the administrative level. This kind of aggregation is popular in several studies, name a few, Besley and Reynal-Querol (2014) , Michalopoulos and Papaioannou (2016) , and Berman, et al (2017) . While I was doing that, I confronted several problems and finally figured them out.
Reference in stackoverflow (Notice that the code on this page could be wrong):</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python III</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/28/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/28/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>In this document, we continue our study on basics of Python.
Method In Python, a method is a function that is associated with an object. It only works with that object It is used with dot notation: object.method()
Check more list methods here String methods here cars = [&amp;#39;Ford&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;BMW&amp;#39;] cars.append(&amp;#39;Mazda&amp;#39;) print(cars) cars.sort() print(cars) Function In Python, a function is a named block of code that performs a specific task or set of operations.</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python II</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/25/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Recap In When a R user began coding with Python I , we learn about:
the IDEs, mathematical operations, basic data types, variables, branching, and iteration comparison and logical operators This document In this document, we push forward the learning process and focus on four data structures used to store and organize data: list, dictionary, and tuple.
List: A list is an ordered collection of items, and it can contain elements of different data types.</description></item><item><title>When a R user began coding with Python I</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/20/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/20/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Excited to start my journey in Python!
I am a R user and always tell myself it is already enough to master one language. But this summer I attended to the ICPSR Sumer Program in Quantitative Methods and enrolled several exciting courses, such as Text Analysis and the Introduction to Python. I thought it’s time to learn something new!
Why Python? Actually, I learn Python because I want to push forward one of my text-analysis projects, which I need to scrap data from Weibo first.</description></item><item><title>News Collection: Climate and Environment</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/05/01/second-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 13:37:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/05/01/second-post/</guid><description>This is a collection of newspaper articles related to climate and the environment, which I am interested in.
Where My Climate Doubts Began to Melt, NYT, Oct/28/2022, link . Global Warming /&amp;amp; Extreme Heat Climate Risks Loom Over Panama Canal, a Vital Global Trade Link, NYT, Aug/25/2023, link . 1. Lack of rain and changing weather patterns are slowing the ship traffic that moves goods around the world.</description></item><item><title>Gendered Corruption: An Analysis of Corruption Cases in China</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/03/20/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/03/20/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Although it has been acknowledged for a while that promoting women&amp;rsquo;s political participation is a requirement for achieving gender equality, recent discussions have emphasized the potential of women&amp;rsquo;s political participation to reduce corruption and improve governance. International organizations such as the World Bank and the United Nations, as well as countries like Mexico, Uganda, and various European countries, view women as possessing higher levels of honesty and integrity, which are essential traits for effective governance[^1].</description></item><item><title>Markdown Testing</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2021/01/07/second-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 13:37:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2021/01/07/second-post/</guid><description>test See the source code of this page if you are interested.
H1 H2 H3 H4 H5 H6 List Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Table Water Water Water Water Water Water Water Water1 Water Water Water Water Quotes What I cannot create, I do not understand2.</description></item></channel></rss>