<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R on Hugo-Du</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/tags/r/</link><description>Recent content in R on Hugo-Du</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 16:00:21 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dupractice.github.io/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Multiple ways to import text data in R</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/09/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/09/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Chapter 2. Vector Data Handling with sf sf
do not need to create simple feature geometry from scratch.
An important feature of an sf object is that it is basically a data.frame with geometric information stored as a variable (column). This means that transforming an sf object works just like transforming a data.frame. Basically, everything you can do to a data.frame, you can do to an sf as well.</description></item><item><title>Multiple ways to import text data in R</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/01/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/08/01/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>Past Reading text files is always the first step when analyzing the text data. However, it could be challenging. Before I get to know the package &amp;lsquo;readtext&amp;rsquo;, I used to write a loop to import data like the following code.
# Step one in this approach is grabbing the list of files. file.list&amp;lt;-list.files() file.list # Step two in this approach is setting up the loop for(i in 1:length(file.list)){ temp&amp;lt;-import(file.list[i]) if(i==1){amdts&amp;lt;-temp} else{amdts&amp;lt;-bind_rows(amdts,temp)} print(paste(&amp;#34;Loading file&amp;#34;,i,&amp;#34;of&amp;#34;,length(file.</description></item><item><title>Gridding data in R</title><link>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/29/bookdown-tips/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 16:00:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://dupractice.github.io/en/2023/07/29/bookdown-tips/</guid><description>I am pushing forward one of my projects, in which I wish to analyze on the grid level instead of on the administrative level. This kind of aggregation is popular in several studies, name a few, Besley and Reynal-Querol (2014) , Michalopoulos and Papaioannou (2016) , and Berman, et al (2017) . While I was doing that, I confronted several problems and finally figured them out.
Reference in stackoverflow (Notice that the code on this page could be wrong):</description></item></channel></rss>